(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T01:30:11.290519",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
AZKi、みんな誕生日おめでとうって言ってくれてありがとう！
AZKi, thank you everyone for wishing me a happy birthday!
一緒に盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped up together!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
そう 見つけた
That's right, I found it
この先だけの世界を
A world that exists only beyond this point
立ち止りかけていた
I was starting to stand still
時を進むための
To keep time moving forward
こんなはずじゃなかった
This isn't how it was supposed to be
ふと漏れた言葉さえ
Even the words that slipped out
あんな日もよかった
Even those days were good
そう思える君がいるよ
Knowing you're here makes me feel that way
消えたくても
Even if I want to disappear
見えなくても
Even if I become invisible
ここに私はいる
I am right here
暗闇の世界さえ越えてく光を
Reaching for the light that crosses even a world of darkness
間違っても
Even if I make mistakes
なくなっても
Even if I lose everything
僕の選ぶ世界
This is the world I choose
思い描いた花じゃなくたって
Even if it's not the flower I envisioned
この手で探すよ
I will search for it with my own hands
みんなお祝いの言葉をありがとう！
Thank you everyone for all the congratulatory words!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
ああ 見つけた
Ah, I found it
なくし掛けてた僕の現在を
My present self that I was almost losing
エンドロールには早すぎると気づいた
I realized it was too early for the end credits
僕だけじゃないんだ 気づけばそばにいたんだ
I wasn't the only one; before I knew it, you were by my side
足跡は続く ほら聞こえる次の音が
Footprints continue; listen, the next sound can be heard
届かなくても 憧れの背に少しだけ追い付いた
Even if it doesn't reach, I caught up just a little bit to the back of my admiration
花と咲くその日まで 思いを歌うよ
I'll sing my feelings until the day flowers bloom
出会いたいそのまた繋がるそんな世界があるよ
There is a world where we meet again and reconnect
次の夜空に光る星々に希望を託そう
Let's entrust our hopes to the stars shining in the next night sky
そう 見つけた
Yes, I found it.
この先だけの世界を
A world existing just beyond.
僕らの地図になかった
It wasn't on our map.
約束できないよ
We can't make promises,
こんな素敵な未来
To a future this wonderful,
想像できないから
Because we couldn't imagine it.
消えかけても 見えなくても
Even if it fades, even if it's unseen,
何度くじけても
No matter how many times we falter,
足跡の伸びる先
Where our footsteps lead ahead,
未来が続くよ
The future will go on.
君が歩くこの道は
The path you walk along
いくつのもの思い出を書き連ねてゆく
weaves together countless memories.
変わることを恐れず
Without fearing change,
不器用でも君だけの道を歩み
walking your own clumsy path.
覚えているよ いつか願った奇跡
I remember the miracle we once wished for,
憧れを詰め込んだ 答えのない旅路の途中
packed with longing, amid an answerless journey.
描いていた物語とは違うけど
It's different from the story I envisioned,
あの時の君に誇れる今日がある
yet I have a today to be proud of before my past self.
何度も悩んで 何度も悔やんだ
After agonizing and regretting so many times,
これまでのすべてが今に繋がる
everything up to now connects to the present.
だから始めよう またここから
So let's start over, right from here,
僕だけが描き続ける夢のようなストーリー
on a dream-like story only I continue to paint.
あの日の君に伝える言葉 それは
The words I want to tell the you of that day:
大丈夫 だからさ 前を向いて進んで
"You'll be fine, so look ahead and move forward."
君が出会うこれからさ
From here on out, in what you encounter,
想像もない物語の初めのページ
lies the opening page of an unimaginable story.
おとぎ話みたいな
Like a fairy tale,
出会いとか別れとか いくつもあるから
with countless meetings and farewells.
僕だけが知ってる答えを
The answer only I knew,
ずっと探し続けて迷ってたんだ
I kept searching for, getting lost along the way.
辿り着いた今日がこんなに
The today I've finally reached is so
愛しくて切なくて ここにいる意味を見つけたよ
dear and bittersweet, I've found the meaning of being here.
あの日から変わらない思いがあるから
Because there's a feeling unchanged since that day,
その涙忘れないで 無駄じゃないから
don't forget those tears, for they aren't in vain.
何度も転んで 何度も抱いて
Falling down and embracing it time and again,
でもそれが君だけの道を開く
still, that opens up your unique path.
だからありがとうと伝えさせて
So let me say thank you,
その一歩踏み出した勇気が始まり
the courage to take that first step is where it begins.
行き着く先にどんな壁があっても
No matter what walls lie ahead,
乗り越えてゆけるから信じて
we can overcome them, so believe in it.
今の僕と君がであったら
If my present self and you were to meet,
どんな言葉をかけてくれる？
what kind of words would you offer me?
君が思う未来とは違うけど
It's different from the future you imagined,
それでも良かったと言えるから
yet I can still say I'm glad it turned out this way.
れでも良かったと言えるから
...can say I'm glad it turned out this way.
描いていた
The story I pictured
あの物語とは違うけど
was different from that tale, yet
あの時の君に誇れる今日がある
I have a today I can proudly show to my past self.
何度も流した
The tears I shed so many times
涙はきっとこれからの宝物に変わるから
will surely turn into future treasures.
あの日から変わらない思いがあるから
Because I hold feelings unchanged since that day,
その勇気忘れないで光になるから
don't forget that courage; it will become your light.
何度も転んでそれでも走って
Falling down time and again, yet still running,
君だけが描き続ける物語だから
because it's a story only you keep drawing,
だからありがとうと伝えたくて
I wanted to say thank you.
これまでの出来事が道しるべになり
The events up until now became guideposts,
どれほど変わっても一つだけのストーリー
No matter how much things change, it's a unique story.
君がいたから今の僕が在るよ
and because you were there, I am here today.
ねえ、またここから描き始めていくんだ
Hey, let's start drawing it from here once again.
こうちゃん、AZKiでーす！
Kou-chan, it's AZKi!
え、今日はAZKi生誕祭ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming to AZKi's birthday live today.
え、1曲目2曲目は「Overtime」と「Existlog」を流させていただきました。
For the first and second songs, we played "Overtime" and "Existlog."
え、今日のハッシュタグはですね、こちらこちらこちらこちら、こちら、「#AZKi生誕祭2022」でぜひつぶやいてくれたら嬉しいです。
Today's hashtag is "#AZKiBirthday2022"—I'd be so happy if you tweeted it out!
はい、今日はね本当にねちょっと、あのゲストもいるし、あのねいろんな発表もありますので、もうねどんどん今日も歌っていきたいと思います。一緒に盛り上がってくれますか？
We have guests and various announcements today, so I want to keep singing more and more. Will you get hyped up with me?
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、次の曲聞いてください。画面の中の君が好き。
With that said, please listen to the next song: "Gamen no Naka no Kimi ga Suki."
君を初めて見つけた時
When I first discovered you,
なぜか心揺さぶられたんだ
for some reason, my heart was shaken.
作り物に命を宿す
Breathing life into a creation—
君の輝きは本物だった
your brilliance was the real deal.
楽しそうな君は素敵だった
You looking so happy was wonderful.
画面の中の君が好き…！
I love the you inside the screen...
画面の中の君が好き…！！
I love the you inside the screen...!
ただ君が笑えたらいい
I just want you to be able to smile.
本当の君とは違うとしても
Even if you might differ from the real-life you,
新しい扉を開けて息をしようよ
let's open a new door and catch our breath.
嘘も本当も関係ないから
Lies and truth don't matter at all,
息をしている瞬間を僕ら見届けたいんだ
so we want to witness every moment you're breathing.
君が好きだから
Because I love you so much.
もしも君が生きづらいなら
If living is hard for you,
好きな顔と服を着てもいい
it's fine to wear your favorite face and clothes.
もしも君が辞めたくなっても
Even if you ever want to quit,
僕らは止めたりしないからさ
we won't try to stop you, so
生きやすい場所を探せばいい
just find a place where it's easy to live.
君の言葉が僕に刺さった
Your words pierced straight through me.
君の歌に僕は揺さぶられた
Your songs shook my soul.
君の配信に僕は夢中になった
I became completely captivated by your streams.
画面の中の君が僕を救ってくれた
The you inside the screen saved me.
いつか画面の外へいなくなっても
Even if you someday leave beyond the screen,
画面の中にいた君のことを
the you who lived within the screen—
君自身が好きでいてくれていたら
if you could love yourself for who you were,
嬉しいな
I'd be so happy.
ただ君が笑えたらいい
I just want you to be able to smile.
本当の君とは違うとしても
Even if you might differ from the real-life you...
君になれたなら 僕は幸せだ
If I could become you, I'd be happy.
幸せだ
So happy.
幸せだから
Because I'm happy.
みんなも一緒に手を振ってね！
Everyone, wave your hands along too!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
猫になって甘やかされたい
I want to become a cat and be pampered.
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved.
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me take a nap as a cat.
起きたら100万登録いってないかな
I wonder if I'll reach 1M subscribers when I wake up.
猫ならばいける 猫ならばいける
If it's as a cat, I can do it!
野ウサギちゃんちゃんとおはようツイートしなくちゃ
Wild rabbit-chan needs to post a good morning tweet.
下書き寝て3時間経って 完璧な140字早々に打ってテリと
3 hours passed sleeping on drafts, typing 140 quick characters...
心折れる平日曜日
A heart-breaking weekday Sunday.
休み無くして稼ぎ続けるそんなの社畜が言うだけ
Working endlessly without rest is just what corporate slaves say.
だからね、よろしくね
So please treat me well.
本質的な甘くして最新マイカチェックしてみてね
Make the essence sweet and check out my latest My-card.
でも今日、早々、本当、眠い、こんなわたしもちゃんと見てほしい
But today is so early and sleepy, I want you to look at even me like this.
もっとあなたの愛が欲しい だから猫になって甘やかされたい
I want more of your love, so I want to become a cat and be pampered.
猫になって甘やかされたい
I want to become a cat and be pampered.
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved.
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me take a nap as a cat.
起きたら100万登録だぜ
When I wake up, it'll be 1M subscribers!
猫になって輝きたいよ 猫になって飼い犬するよ
I want to shine as a cat! I'll be your pet dog.
もっと君に伝わりますように
Hoping it reaches you even more.
猫ならばいける 猫ならばいける
If it's as a cat, I can do it!
お散歩してたら公園で 可愛いワンちゃん見つけたよ
While taking a walk in the park, I found a cute puppy.
誰よどうしたら吠えられた
Who are you? Why did it bark at me?
やっぱ猫になりたい
I still want to become a cat.
でもどうすればいい 猫のなり方
But what should I do? How to become a cat?
ぐずねと出ない本当にして欲しい 作る作ってほしい
I want you to make me a real non-fretful...
だから猫になって抱きしめられたい 猫になって撫で撫でしてよ
So I want to become a cat and be hugged, to be petted.
猫になって餌を抑えて
Become a cat and hold down the food,
山盛りチュールはよろしくね
A mountain of Churu, please treat it well.
猫になって感謝してタイム 猫になって笑い合おうよ
Become a cat and thank me for the time, let's laugh together.
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats even more!
本当やばい 起きたら12時
Seriously terrible, woke up at 12.
どううん寝過ぎてるでも暇しがない
Slept way too much, but I've got plenty of free time.
逆に二度寝しましただから
So I went back to sleep a second time, that's why.
だから猫になって甘やかされたい
So I want to become a cat and be pampered.
猫になって甘やかされたい
I want to become a cat and be pampered.
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved.
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me take a nap as a cat.
起きたら100万登録だぜ
When I wake up, it'll be 1M subscribers!
猫になって輝きたいよ 猫になって飼い犬するよ
I want to shine as a cat! I'll be your pet dog.
もっと君に伝わりますように
Hoping it reaches you even more.
もっともっと 猫になって甘やかされたいずっと
More and more, I want to become a cat and be pampered forever.
猫になって抱きしめられたい もっと
I want to become a cat and be hugged more.
猫になって感謝してタイム 猫になって笑い合おうよ
Become a cat and thank me for the time, let's laugh together.
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats even more!
猫ならばいける 君となら行ける
If it's as a cat, I can do it! With you, I can go!
ボイストだよ！
Voice to you!
みんな行くよ！
Here we go, everyone!
にゃーーっ！
Meow!
というわけで、2曲連続でお届けしました！
And with that, we've brought you two songs in a row!
みんな一緒ににゃあにゃあしてくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you all for meowing along with us!
はい、ごめんの中の君は好きと、そして猫ならばいけるの2曲をお届けしました！
Yes, we brought you 'Kimi wa Suki' and 'Neko Naraba Ikeru'!
はい、あ、ちょっと飛ばしてきたので、お水を飲んでもいいですか？
So, um, I kinda sped through that, so can I drink some water?
お水、お水補給します。
Water, I'll take a water break.
はい、みなさん、それではね、お待たせかと思うんですけど
Alright everyone, so, I think you've been waiting for this,
ゲストをここで、お呼びしたいと思います！
We'd like to invite our guest here!
いいですか？みなさん準備いいですか？
Is that okay? Is everyone ready?
それでは…そらちゃーーん！
Then... Sora-chaaaan!
あー！ありがとーー！そらちゃんが来てくれましたー！
Ah! Thank youuu! Sora-chan came!
また会えた！あえて嬉しい！
We met again! So happy to see you!
ありがとう！今日来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you for coming today!
そらちゃーーん！にゃあにゃあお願いします！
Sora-chaaaan! Please do the 'nyaa nyaa'!
あ、そらちゃん、アイドル衣装じゃないですか？
Ah, Sora-chan, aren't you wearing your idol outfit?
そうなんですよう！
That's right!
じゃあ私も、アイドル衣装に着替えてきていいかな？
Then can I go change into my idol outfit too?
いいよー！行ってきすごーい！
Sure! Go ahead!
よいしょ、よいしょ、待って衣装、どんな衣装だと思う？みんな知ってると思うんだよね。
Heave-ho, wait, what kind of outfit do you think it is? I think everyone knows.
よいしょ、よいしょ。あ、もうね、準備ができたみたいですね。
Heave-ho. Ah, looks like she's ready.
そうだね、もう早い着替えのプロなんで。
That's right, I'm a pro at quick changes.
あずき！はーい！
AZKi! Hiiii!
やったーー！黒と白でね、アイドル衣装で今日は…
Yay! In black and white, idol outfits today...
そらちゃんと一緒に歌っていきたいと思います！
...we'd like to sing together with Sora-chan!
あ、ピース！みんな！ピース！いぇーーい！
Ah, peace! Everyone! Peace! Yeaah!
今日はこの、ね、二人が揃ったということで、あの曲をやります！
Since the two of us are together today, we'll do THAT song!
はーい！お水飲もう！
Yes! Let's drink water!
お水はいくら飲んでもいいものですからね。
Water is something you can drink as much as you want.
みんなもしっかり水分補給しながら見るんだよ！
Everyone, make sure to watch while staying hydrated!
ということで、一緒にタイトルコールしてくれますか？はい！
So, will you do the title call with us? Yes!
せーの、紅藍クロニクル！
Ready, set, Kurenai Chronicle!
雲間に隠れた無数の星よ
Countless stars hidden among the clouds,
今、君はどこで輝いているんだろう
where are you shining right now?
荒野を彷徨う無数の旅は
Countless journeys wandering the wilderness,
今、僕をどこへ連れて行くのだろう
where are they taking me now?
僕らが出会うため（世界中で）
So that we could meet (across the world),
共に生きていくため（ふたりきり）
so that we could live together (just the two of us),
だって、この空の先（どこまでも）
because beyond this sky (no matter how far),
呼び覚ませ心根にあるものを
awaken what lies deep in our hearts!
殻を破り飛び立つように
Like breaking out of a shell to take flight,
果てない藍が闇を穿く煌めく光になれ
endless indigo pierces the darkness, becoming a radiant light!
悲しさと寂しさに雨打たれても辿り着く音確かな旋律
Even if beaten by the rain of sorrow and loneliness, we reach a sure melody—
それはきっと嘘じゃないここでいつまでもいつまでもふたり歌い合おう
that surely isn't a lie! Let's keep singing together here, forever and ever!
誰にも見せない弱さがほらこぼれては力に変わっていくから
The weakness we show to no one overflows and turns into strength,
誰かを信じる勇気はもう振り切って前へと進むだけなんだ
so our courage to believe in someone just pushes us straight ahead!
誰にも見せない弱さがほら
The weakness we show to no one,
こぼれては力に変わっていくから
overflows and turns into strength,
誰かを信じる勇気はもう
so the courage to believe in someone,
振り切って前へと進むだけなんだ
pushes us straight ahead!
僕らが
We
この世界は
in this world
巡るよ
revolve.
変わりなんていないから
Because there is no replacement,
リアルなんだ
it's real.
だって この魂には
Because in this soul,
本物の
true
絆も 常識も
bonds and common sense...
壁を越えて 闘うように
Like fighting across walls,
果てないヤバい胸をつらぬく
piercing through a bottomless, dangerous heart—
約束を胸に染み慣れ
let the promise soak into your chest.
愛しさや 切なさを覚えていくの
Learning to remember fondness and heartache,
作り出せよ 確かなハモり
create a sure harmony.
これは生き得た証だから
This is proof that we managed to live, so
声を聞かせてよ 聞かせてよ
let me hear your voice, let me hear it.
二人歌い合う
The two of us singing together—
美しく燃え上がる炎よ
O flame burning so brilliantly,
青空へどう咲く花よ
O flower blooming toward the blue sky,
互いに手と手重ねて
overlapping hands with each other,
ここに歌え 叫べ 今
sing and shout right here, right now!
果てない愛は 僕らつらぬく
Endless love pierces through us,
消えない記憶になれ 愛しさや 切なさを 抱えたままで
becoming an indelible memory, holding onto fondness and heartache.
たどり着くほどの 確かなメロディ
A melody certain enough to reach the destination—
これは生き得た証だから
this is proof that we managed to live,
今も聞こえている 聞こえてるよ ふたりだけの歌
and it's still audible, I can hear it, our song for just the two of us.
未練レコード 作詞・作曲：40mP
[Miren Record - Lyrics & Music: 40mP]
まだほんのちょっと未練がましく
Still a little bit clinging to the past,
キミが好きだった歌をかけてみる
I try playing the song you used to love.
すっかり乾いたアスファルトの匂い
The smell of completely dried asphalt,
ただ空回った車がひとつ
and just a single spinning car.
アガガストラトノ
Ah, a Stratocaster...
泣き声が響いた
echoing with cries.
「私の名前なんて忘れていいよ」
"You can forget my name,"
切り替し降る花のように
like falling flowers turning over,
だけどいつかこの歌を聴く時は
but someday, when you hear this song,
ねぇ 隣に誰かがいたこと思い出して
hey, remember that someone was by your side.
押し込み忘れてた最後の言葉
The final words I forgot to push away—
無理に強がって笑ってみせたけど
though I forced myself to act strong and smile,
私が付き合っていた頃よりも
even more than when we were together,
幸せに乗って欲しくはないのよ
I don't want you to ride on happiness.
心を蹴飛ばした
I kicked away my heart,
初デートの写真もペアリングも
throwing away our first date photos and matching rings
簡単に捨てられたのに
so easily, yet...
胸に刻まれた歌声のせいで
because of the singing voice carved into my chest,
またキミの笑顔思い出してしめつけるの
I remember your smile once again, and it tightens my heart.
まだほんのちょっと未練がましく
Still just a little bit lingering,
キミが好きだった歌をかけてみる
I try playing the song you used to love.
動かなくなった柱時計の針
The hands of the grandfather clock stopped moving,
ただ空回りした歯車がひとつ
And just a single gear spins idly.
ストラトの泣き声が響いた
The crying voice of the Stratocaster echoed.
プレイリストから消去しようとして
Trying to delete it from my playlist,
でも、それすらもできなくて
Even that was too much for me to do.
どうせ忘れることはできないから
Since I won't be able to forget anyway,
未練がましく生きてゆく
I'll live on with lingering attachments.
せめて次にこの歌を聴くときは
At least the next time I hear this song,
ねえ、今よりも上手に笑えるように
Hey, so I can smile more skillfully than now,
ねえ、最後まで涙を流さないように
Hey, so I won't shed tears until the very end.
ということで、そらちゃんオリジナル曲「未練レコード」をお二人でお届けしました！
With that, Sora-chan and I performed her original song "Miren Record"!
いぇーい！
Yay!
そらちゃんありがとう！
Thank you, Sora-chan!
楽しかった！
It was so fun!
一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかった！
I was so happy to sing together!
ちょっとまたあとで呼ぶね？
I'll call you again later, okay?
本当？
Really?
うん！
Yeah!
やったー！
Yay!
じゃああとで呼ぶね！
Then I'll call you later!
ありがとう！おめでとー！
Thank you! Happy birthday!
はい、ということでね、皆さんね、今日のサムネイルで分かっていると思いますが、次のゲストをお呼びしたいと思います！
Now then, as you probably know from today's thumbnail, I'd like to invite our next guest!
いきましょう！すいちゃーん！
Let's go! Suichan!
いぇーい！
Yay!
星街すいせいでーす！AZKiちゃんお誕生日おめでとー！
It's Hoshimachi Suisei! Happy birthday, AZKi-chan!
今日もかわいい！
You're so cute today too!
AZKiちゃん誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday, AZKi-chan!
ありがとう、来てくれて！うれしい！
Thank you for coming! I'm so happy!
それとね、もう一つね、私には言いたいことがあります。
And also, there's one more thing I want to say.
なになに？
What is it?
ホロライブへようこそ！
Welcome to Hololive!
そうなんですよ、もう3ヶ月経ってしまったんですけど。
That's right, it's already been 3 months though.
そうなんですよ、そうなんです。なんで今日ちょっとね、今日は、そらちゃんとすいちゃんを呼んで、ライブをしたいと思って。
Indeed. That's why today, I wanted to invite Sora-chan and Sui-chan to do a live stream.
そう、なんかさ、もうめっちゃエモい気持ちになっちゃって。
Yeah, like, I got so emotional.
1曲目からさ、もうなんかステージがこのホロライブアリーナになったから、すごいめっちゃ解説してくれて。
Right from the first song, the stage became this Hololive Arena, and you explained so much.
うわー、崩れ落ちる。一般通過の星街さん。
Whoa, I'm collapsing. Hoshimachi-san passing by.
本当にすごい感動しました。ありがとうございます！
I was truly so moved. Thank you so much!
すいちゃんがね、来てくれたということで、あの曲を、あの曲を歌いたいなと思って。
Since Sui-chan came, I wanted to sing that song, that particular song.
歌いましょう！あります！
Let's sing it! We definitely have it!
はい！じゃあ、ていーちに付くぞ。
Yes! Alright, let's get into position.
ここだ！
Right here!
では、タイトルコール一緒にしていただけますか？
Now, could you do the title call together with me?
はい！
Yes!
せーの！『The Last Frontier』！
Ready, set! "The Last Frontier"!
未知の期待抱え出会ったあの日の僕らは
The two of us who met carrying unknown expectations back then,
底に湧き上がる何かを言葉にできなくて
Could not put into words what welled up from the bottom of our hearts.
僕ら、気づいたときには遠く離れてて
Before we knew it, we had drifted far apart,
もう、再び会うことないと思っていた
Thinking we would never meet again.
でも、聞こえていたよ
Yet, I could hear it all along—
君が歌を歌うからずっと
Because you kept singing your song.
孤独な星たちへ捧げる歌を
A song dedicated to the lonely stars,
一人で最果てへ旅立つ歌を
A song for journeying alone to the farthest ends,
交わることのない世界を
A world that would never intersect,
今変えるから最後に君と僕で出会う
We will change it now, and finally, you and I will meet.
街は別れを想い描いた
The streets pictured our parting,
風が冷たくて
As the wind grew cold.
晴れない灰色の街をただ
Just gazing at the gray town,
眺め続けていた
Which would never clear up.
僕らは何を信じたらよかったんだろう
What should we have believed in all this time?
きっと立ち止まることは諦めることだ
Surely, to stop in our tracks is to give up.
でも忘れないように君に言葉紡ぐから
But I'll weave words for you so I never forget.
超えて
Crossing over...
水平線の先 目指す場所まで
To the place beyond the horizon we aim for,
光りだったのか まだ辿り着くまで
Until we finally reach whatever light there is.
バラバラに砕けた破片をここに集めたわ
I gathered up the shattered fragments here,
遠い日へ還るから
Returning to distant days.
響かせよう 僕らの今を
Let's make our present resonate!
さよなら 別れの日 星屑の星座駆け行く日に
On the day of parting, racing through stardust,
愛にいく
We go to meet love.
強くこたえそうの氷はいつか終わるこの世界から
From this world where the ice will someday end,
愛を伝えにゆく
We go to convey our love.
最前線の地 君なら行ける
To the front lines—you can go there,
まだ見たことのない世界へ行ける
To a world you've never seen before.
僕は観測する 輝きやまぬ星の名を
I will observe the name of the star that shines.
Remember the Frontier 愛する星たちへ捧げる歌を
Offering a song to the stars we love,
旅立つ歌を
A song for setting out on a journey.
バラバラに砕けた破片をここに集めたわ
I gathered up the shattered fragments here,
遠い日へ還るから
Returning to distant days.
遥か から 響かせよう 僕らの今を
From afar, let's make our present resonate!
歌う
Singing...
天球、彗星は夜を跨いで
Celestial Sphere, the Comet Straddles the Night
灯りがひとつともった
A single light flickered on,
手をいろどった病気が綺麗だ
The painted disease on my hand is so beautiful.
僕の吐いた白い息のように 消してしまえたらな
If only I could erase it like my breath in the cold air.
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Suppressing it, I sank deep down.
泣き声さえ聞こえているから 君をさした あの日もずっと
Even your voice is heard, ever since that day I pointed at you.
僕の青色で塗りつぶして
Paint it all over with my blue,
全部涙になって 星の海を流れていった
Until everything turned to tears, flowing through a sea of stars.
そっと青を添えたら
If I gently add blue to it,
彗星が突然と跨いだ
A comet suddenly straddled
誰もいない夜の空を
The empty night sky.
深く沈まった街の中へ 降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Into the sunken town, whose sorrow is it falling down?
星はまだ声を描いてそんだ
The stars were still tracing voices.
いつか還るなんて言えなかった
I couldn't say we'd return someday.
星がほぐした後の街を
The town after the stars untangled it...
黒く澄んだからんどもの空を
The hollow, darkly tarnished sky,
箒星が彩るように
as if colored by a comet,
君を刺した不安も苦痛も
The anxiety and pain that pierced you,
僕の青色で塗り潰して
paint them over with my blue,
君の涙をそっと
gently pouring your tears
星の海に流し込むんだ
into the sea of stars.
尾を引いたその光が誰かをまた救うから
That light trailing a tail will save someone once again.
彗星がどこへ向かうなら
If a comet is heading somewhere,
この空を君にあげる
I will give you this sky.
言えなかった言葉の尾を引いて
Drawing out the tail of words I couldn't say,
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう？
whose sadness is falling down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
A star flew, drawing an arc once more,
街の視線を奪い去るように
as if stealing away the gaze of the town.
君とまた会えるなら僕はそうだな
If I can meet you again, I'd say...
星の名前をひとつ受け止めよう
Let's accept one name of a star.
悲しみが溢れそうになること
When sadness is about to overflow,
天球で離れ離れでも
even if we are separated across the celestial sphere,
僕らは繋がっているから
because we are connected.
彗星がすぐ近くを飛んだ
A comet flew right beside us,
誰もいない夜の空を埋めた
filling the empty night sky.
深く沈み澄んだ街の中へ
Into the deeply sinking, clear town,
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう？
whose sadness is falling down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ もやのかかった思考を晴らして
A star flew, drawing an arc once more, clearing away hazy thoughts.
“いつかまた会える” なんて言えなかった
I couldn't say "We'll meet again someday."
星が降ったあとの街、僕はもうずっと君の行方を捜してた
In the town after the stars fell, I have always been searching for your whereabouts.
ってことで、すいちゃんオリジナル曲「天球、彗星は夜を跨いで」をお二人でお届けしました！
And so, the two of us performed Sui-chan's original song "Tenkyuu, Suisei wa Yoru o Mataide"!
イェーイ！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
もう本当にこの曲はすいちゃんのことを知って初めて聴いたそう…
Really, this is the first song I heard after getting to know Sui-chan...
聞いたときの曲で、めちゃくちゃなんかとても思い出深くて
and it holds so many deep memories for me.
いや懐かしい！本当私はいのあか入る前とかにね
Man, so nostalgic! Honestly, even before joining INNK...
あの、あずきちが紹介した時とかがあって、もうそこで聴いた曲を絶対いつかそのすいちゃんと歌いたいなと思っていて
AZKi introduced it, and ever since I heard it there, I always thought I wanted to sing it with Sui-chan someday.
今日はちょっとこの選曲をしてまいりました！
So I chose this song for today!
これはエモいです！
That's so emotional!
ありがとうございます！一緒に歌ってくれて
Thank you so much for singing it with me!
はい、ということでですね、皆さん次の曲はゲストみんなで歌いたいと思いますので、そらちゃんを呼びたいと思います！そらちゃーん！
Right, so everyone, for our next song, we want to sing with all our guests, so let's call out Sora-chan! Sora-chan!
そらちゃーん！素晴らしかったー！
Sora-chan! That was wonderful!
一発すずかの空？
One-shot Suzuki sky?
いやあ、素晴らしかったな！なんかね、ちょっと袖にいるねそらちゃん見えたんですけど、もうなんかうってきてた
Man, that was wonderful! I saw Sora-chan standing in the wings, and she looked so moved.
そらもめっちゃよかった！え、ありがとうございます！めっちゃよかった！すいちゃんも「パッパッパッパラッパッパ」
Sora was amazing too! - Ah, thank you! - She was great! And Sui-chan's "Pa-pa-pa-para-pa-pa..."
まじで歌ってなかった？ねえ、あの、イケメンなすいちゃんで「パッパッパッパラッパッパ」
Were you actually singing? That handsome Sui-chan going "Pa-pa-pa-para-pa-pa..."
はい、ということでですね、今日は3人揃ったので、あずきのオリジナル曲を一緒に今日は歌ってもらいたいと思います！
Right, so since the three of us are gathered today, we'd like you all to sing AZKi's original song together with us!
次の曲聴いてください、「Intersection」！
Please listen to our next song, "Intersection"!
溺れたいな i gotcha ギュッと
I want to drown in you, i gotcha tightly
ハマる君の交差点
At your intersection where I get hooked
変わりたいな気持ちもっと
I want to change, wanting to feel more
yellow ちょいアブないね
Yellow, a bit dangerous, right?
ネオンの眩しい夜
The dazzling night of neon
もう行かななくちゃいけない
We have to go now,
永く遠い道の終わり
at the end of a long, distant road.
静かに眠った
Sleeping quietly.
君の体温を探したわ
I searched for your warmth,
アスファルトで踏み潰したフロア
on the asphalt-crushed floor.
その手探りだ 調和するように
Fumbling in the dark to harmonize.
気にしないでなんて言わないで
Don't tell me not to worry.
本当はいつも正直じゃできないけど
Though I'm not always honest.
気がついてよなんて言えなくて
I couldn't say, "Please notice me."
嘘ばかり 溺れたいな
Filled with lies, I want to drown.
アイガッタキョウト ハマる君の交差点
I got ya, at your intersecting streets.
壊れたいな 気持ちもっと ブルー 飲み干す体
I want to break, feeling more blue, drinking it all in.
認めてたいな アイワナキョウト かなりギリの通過点
I want to admit it, I wanna get you at this critical waypoint.
変わりたいな 気持ちもっと イエロー 譲り合わないで
I want to change, feeling more yellow, without yielding.
絶望と怪滅の間
Between despair and destruction,
永遠と快楽の狭間 いつもじゃないすれ違いを ホワイト黒くするリフレクション
between eternity and pleasure, reflecting white into black.
感覚麻痺ってどうした
What happened to my numbed senses?
そんなにいずらせんなよ コラコラ クラクラ 嫌い生き絶えだらり
Don't fidget so much, dizzy and exhausted.
ダラリクラリもいいじゃないかと
Isn't it fine to just laze around?
消えない染みと言い訳吐いて 耳の奥そこで繰り返す
Spitting excuses and indelible stains, repeating deep in my ears.
イヤホンで聞き飽きた曲が
The song I grew tired of hearing on my earphones
そのリピートを 破壊するように
shatters that repeat loop.
気にしないでなんて言わないで
Don't tell me not to worry.
本当はいつも正直じゃないけど 気がついてよなんて言えなくて
Though I'm not always honest, I couldn't say, "Please notice me."
嘘ばかり 溺れたいな
Filled with lies, I want to drown.
アイガッタキョウト ハマる君の交差点 壊れたいな 気持ちもっと ブルー 飲み干す体
I got ya, at your intersecting streets. I want to break, feeling more blue.
認めてたいな アイワナキョウト かなりギリの通過点
I want to admit it, I wanna get you at this critical waypoint.
変わりたいな 気持ちもっと イエロー 譲り合わないで
I want to change, feeling more yellow, without yielding.
変わりたいな 気持ちもっと イエロー ちょい待てないね
I want to change, feeling more yellow, I can't wait a second longer.
最後ありがとう！
Thank you at the very end!
てことで、AZKiオリジナル曲「Intersection」を3人でお届けしました！
So, the three of us delivered AZKi's original song "Intersection"!
わあ！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
嬉しい！
So happy!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
本当に本当に今日は3人とこうやってライブをすることができて、めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです。
I'm so, so happy we got to perform live together with the three of us today.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
そらちゃんどうでしたか、今日は？
Sora-chan, how was today for you?
いや、なんかね、AZKiちゃんの誕生日ということで、今日はねすごい気合を入れてがんばっ
Well, since it's AZKi-chan's birthday, I put a lot of spirit into doing my best—
嬉しい！そうなんだ、すごいなんか、ちょっとIntersectionをね、知らなくて、ですごい頑張って覚えてきてくれて、めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです。
I'm so glad! She didn't know "Intersection" at first, but she worked so hard to learn it for us, and I was so happy.
めちゃくちゃ緊張...
I was so nervous...
めちゃくちゃ、アップアップ...って、すごく緊張したんですけど、一生懸命楽しませていただきました。
I was struggling so much... I was extremely nervous, but I did my absolute best to enjoy it.
一生懸命ダンスを教えていただきました！
She taught us the choreography so hard!
よかったよー！
You did great!
よかったよ！楽しかった！
It was so fun!
すいちゃんもありがとう！おめでとう！
Sui-chan, thank you too! Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして、すいちゃんどうでしたか、今日は？
And Sui-chan, how was today for you?
いや、すいちゃんはね、今日の1曲目と2曲目を見て、うわ、そうだ！AZKiちゃんと会ったのはこんな時だった！って思い出して。
Well, seeing the first and two songs today, I thought, "Oh right! That's when I first met AZKi-chan!"
本当だね！
That's right!
思ってさ、ほらさ、なんかさ、昔の小さな事務所時代を思い出すよ。ね？もう小さな部屋でさ、なんか一緒に話したり練習したりとか、色々思い出しました。
Thinking about it, it reminds me of the small office days in the past. Right? In a small room, talking and practicing together, it brought back so many memories.
色々思い出しました。
So many memories.
改めてね、お誕生日と、ほら、ライブ加入と、これからね、色々あると思いますけど、頑張っていただけたらなと思います！
Once again, happy birthday, joining the live performances, and I'm sure there's a lot ahead for you, but I hope you'll keep doing your best!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
そらちゃん、今日は1日ありがとうございました！ありがとうございます！
Sora-chan, thank you so much for today! Thank you!
おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
では、ここでお別れになりますが、また、やろうねライブ！
Well, it's time to say goodbye here, but let's do another live show!
やろう！
Let's do it!
やろう！やろう！
じゃあ、またね、追い越してくれてありがとう！
Well, see you again, thank you for overtaking us!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いくぞ！そらちゃん！
Here we go, Sora-chan!
ぬーん！
Nuun!
ぬ、元気のいいぬんが聞こえてきましたが。
I heard a spirited "Nuun!" there.
はい、そろそろ、え、生誕祭ライブも終盤となりました。
Yes, the birthday live is coming to an end soon.
え、皆さんにここで重大発表をしたいと
Um, I have an important announcement...
伝えたいことがありますので、ここで発表していきたいと思います。
and something I want to tell everyone, so I'd like to announce it now.
それでは、いきます。
Well then, here we go.
こちらです！
Here it is!
AZKi 4ヶ月連続デジタルシングル リリース決定！！
AZKi's 4-month consecutive digital single release!
こんちゃっ！デジタルシングルリリース決定いたしました！
Hello! A digital single release has been decided!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
えー、第1弾は「afterglow」、2022年7月3日24時から配信開始いたします。
The 1st single is "afterglow," starting distribution on July 3, 2022 at 24:00.
そして、こちらの新曲MVが本日この後22時15分にプレミア公開されます！
And the music video for this new song will premiere tonight at 22:15!
えー、デジタル配信とMV合わせてぜひ見て聴いてくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could check out both the digital release and the MV.
はい、ということで本日はですねこちらの新曲を今ここでですね披露しようと思います。
Yes, so today, I'm going to perform this new song right here, right now.
お、その前に、お水飲んでいいですか？
Ah, before that, can I have a drink of water?
お水飲んで行きたいと思います。
I'll drink some water and get going.
それでは皆さん、新曲聴いてください。「afterglow」
Now everyone, please listen to the new song, "afterglow."
もう行かなくちゃいけない
I have to go now.
長く遠い道の終わり
At the end of a long, distant road,
静かに眠った
sleeping peacefully,
おでこを合わせて深く息をした
we pressed our foreheads together and took a deep breath.
見上げた先には赤い空
Looking up, there was a red sky.
きっと同じ空を見ているのかな
I wonder if you're looking at the same sky.
胸に残る
Linger in my heart,
あなたのあなたのあなたの声が今
your, your, your voice now
夢に落ちて
falling into a dream,
夢で覚める
waking up in a dream.
あなたのあなたのあなたの記憶
Your, your, your memories
今私を置いていく
are now leaving me behind.
ほら幸せなことは
Look, happy things
すぐに消えてしまうようで
seem to disappear so quickly.
あんなに好きだった景色も音楽も色褪せてしまった
The scenery and music I loved so much have faded away.
今を生きていくこと
Living in the present,
一人ひたすら走ること
running forward all alone,
私という存在は脆くてその足動かない
my existence is so fragile, my feet won't move.
見上げた先には灰の空
Looking up, there was an ash-colored sky.
ちゃんと色を取り戻せるように世界の中
In the world, so I can properly bring back the colors,
あなたのあなたのあなたの声が今こだまする
your, your, your voice now echoes.
世界の中あなたのあなたのあなたの欠片今私は探している
In the world, your, your, your fragments, right now I am searching for them.
胸に残る
Linger in my heart,
あなたのあなたのあなたの声が今空に溶けていく
your, your, your voice is now dissolving into the sky.
夢で覚める
Waking up in a dream,
あなたのあなたのあなたの記憶今私を忘れていく
your, your, your memories are now forgetting me.
きっと良かった
Surely it was for the best,
これで最後
this is the end.
もう行かなくちゃ
I have to go now,
夢が終わる
the dream ends.
てことで 新曲「アフターグロー」をお聞きいただきました。
And with that, you've heard our new song, "Afterglow."
こちらの新曲は AZKiが作詞作曲しております。
This new song has lyrics and music written by AZKi.
作詞は瀬名航さんと一緒に、そして瀬名航さんに編曲していただきました。いかがだったでしょうか。
The lyrics were written together with Sena Kou-san, and Sena Kou-san arranged it. How did you like it?
私のいる世界もみんなの世界もどんどんね、こう時間の流れと共に変わっていっていると思うんですけど、
My world and everyone's world are changing steadily along with the passage of time.
まなんかその中でなんかなごり惜しかったこととか、なんかそういうことがたくさんあって、でもそれにこう別れを告げなきゃいけない、
Amidst all that, there were many things I felt reluctant to part with, yet we have to say goodbye to them.
そんなことをこの曲に込めました。たくさん聞いてくれると嬉しいです。
I put those feelings into this song. I'd be happy if you listened to it a lot.
え、AZKi誕生日グッズがでます！こちらです！
Um, AZKi's birthday merchandise is coming out! Here it is!
はい、そしてここで告知、2つ目あります！皆さんお待たせいたしました！
Yes, and now for the second announcement! Everyone, thank you for waiting!
ホロライブに移籍してからの初めてのグッズ、初めての直筆サインもあります。ぜひ手に入れてください。
These are the first goods and the first autographed goods since transferring to Hololive. Please be sure to get them.
内容は、B2タペストリー、そしてランダムアクリルキーホルダー、
The contents are: a B2 tapestry, a random acrylic keychain,
タンブラー、そしてコースター！ステーションボイスがついてフルセットで！
a tumbler, and a coaster! Station voice included in the full set!
直筆サイン入りポストカードが数量限定になりますのでぜひお早めに購入してください。
The autographed postcard is in limited quantity, so please purchase early.
そして、フルセットね、サインがないほうも、複製サイン入りポストカードを箱押しで入れておりますので、
And for the full set without the autograph, it also includes a postcard with a printed facsimile signature embossed on it.
どうぞよろしくお願いします！販売開始はこのあと22時からとなっております。よろしくお願いします！
Sales will start tonight at 10 PM. Thank you very much!
ということで、早いものでライブも残り1曲となりました。
And with that, time flies, and we are down to our final song of the live.
ちょっとね最後の挨拶に、ちょっと皆さんから私からなんか色々お伝えしたいなと思います。
Before the final greeting, I wanted to share various things with you all from my side.
去年、12月にイノナカミュージック終了を発表してですね、今年4月にホロライブに移籍してからも今日この誕生日ライブを迎えるまでたくさんのことがありまして、
Last year in December, we announced the closure of INNK Music, and after transferring to Hololive this April, a lot has happened until today's birthday live.
イノナカミュージック終了にあたってはですね、AZKiの活動をやめるべきかと考えたり、卒業することが本当はきれいな終わりだったかもしれないと何度も思ったことがありました。今でもどこかでそうしていたほうがよかったんじゃないかと思うことがあります。
Regarding the conclusion of INNK Music, I sometimes wondered if I should stop my activities, or if graduating was the cleaner ending. Even now, I sometimes wonder if that was better.
でも開拓者の皆さんがいてくれて、ホロライブのみんながいてくれて、今のAZKiがおり、今日このステージに立つことができています。今日こうやって4回目の誕生日を一緒に迎えてくれてありがとう。
But thanks to the Kaitakusha and everyone in Hololive, the present AZKi exists, and I can stand on this stage. Thank you for celebrating my 4th birthday together.
本当にAZKiはみんながいなければここにいませんでした。AZKiはAZKiの世界を続けてこれませんでした。私は本当にこの世界が大好きです。歌うことも大好きです。これからもどんな形でであれ作り上げてきた音楽とか作品とかを大切にして活動していきたいと思っています。
Truly, without everyone, AZKi wouldn't be here, and couldn't have continued her world. I truly love this world and singing. I want to continue cherishing the music and works we've built up.
それでは今日最後の曲、聞いてください。「いのち」。
Now then, please listen to today's final song, "Inochi."
息をしている 君は生きている
You are breathing, you are alive.
当然のこと 誰も疑わないの 息をしている
It's a natural thing, no one doubts it, you are breathing.
ように見えている 性能の裏側 私にとっての何か
Appearing as if... Behind the performance, something precious to me...
心臓がドクドクしている 叩かれても重ならずに
My heart is beating wildly, even when beaten, without piling up...
此処で歌うよ ボタン一つの 命
I will sing right here, life at the push of a button.
最後まで私の方こそ覚えているねの
To the very end, I'm the one who remembers, you know.
消えてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよねぇ
It feels like it might vanish, understand it, please understand.
本当のことなの 恋い焦がしは時間がそう
It's the truth, yearning is just time doing that.
君が忘れちゃったら 私はいなくなるの 命のような 夢を見てるよ
If you forget, I will disappear, seeing a dream like life...
またね バイバイ
See you, bye-bye.
息をしている
You are breathing...
I am breathing,
君は生きている
you are alive.
当たり前のこと 誰も疑わないの
It's something no one ever doubts.
息をしているように 見えている
It looks as though you're breathing.
生の裏側 私にとっての 何か
Behind life, something meant just for me.
鼓動が ドクドク している
My heartbeat is pounding away.
叩かれても 腐らずに 此処で 歌うよ
Even if beaten down, without rotting, I'll sing right here.
ボタン一つの いのち
Life, hanging on a single button.
最期までの 私のこと 覚えてて くれる の ？
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまい そうな の わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
I feel like I'm about to fade away, understand me, please understand.
本物の とこ どうなの ？ 恋と推しは 違う ん でしょ ？
How is it really? Love and an oshi are different, right?
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I'll disappear.
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.
息をしている だから生きている
Breathing, therefore I'm alive,
自己証明を 欲し가っているんだ
craving self-affirmation.
音が止まって 動かなくなって
When the music stops and I can no longer move,
そんな 私を 君は 笑ってくれるかな ？
will you smile at someone like me?
鼓動が ドクドク している
My heartbeat is pounding away.
嫌われても 腐らずに 此処で 歌うよ
Even if hated, without rotting, I'll sing right here.
気分次第の いのち
Life, dependent on mood.
最期までの 私のこと 見届けて くれる の ？
Will you see me through to the very end?
覚めてしまい そうな の わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
I feel like I'm waking up, understand me, please understand.
声が聞こえる んだよ 鹹い涙が出ちゃうほど
I can hear your voice, enough to bring salty tears.
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I'll disappear.
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.
ふさぎこんだ あの日を 軽くいじらないで やめて
Don't make light of that gloomy day, stop it.
それが生きる 糧になるから
Because it becomes nourishment to live.
大丈夫 ずっと 私は歌い続けるから
It's okay, I'll keep on singing forever.
最期までの 私も生きているか わからない けど
Even if I don't know if I'll live until the very end,
君がくれた 言葉は 確実 に 残ってる
the words you gave me definitely remain.
最期までの 私のこと 覚えてて くれる の ？
Will you remember me until the very end?
いつか死んでしまう だろう わからない わからない よ ねぇ
Someday I might die, I don't know, I really don't know, hey.
痛い くらい 気持ちが シンクロ する 時 も ある けど
Even when our feelings sync up to a painful degree,
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
if you forget me, I'll disappear.
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.
最期までの 私のこと 覚えてて くれる の ？
Will you remember me until the very end?
いつか死んでしまう だろう わからない わからない よ ねぇ
Someday I might die, I don't know, I really don't know, hey.
痛い くらい 気持ちが シンクロ する 時 も ある けど
Even when our feelings sync up to a painful degree,
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
if you forget me, I'll disappear.
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.